

07421064886 jdarby1983@icloud.com 112 Churchfield Lane, Barnsley, South Yorkshire, S75 5DN

Diligent, Resourceful and Certified Senior Network Engineer/Architect

I'm an enthusiastic senior network engineer/architect with proficiency in network design, technical pre-sales, consultancy and 3rd line support.

With a career spanning over a decade, I have garnered excellent organisational skills, commercial awareness and working knowledge of the networking industry and technologies. I possess the necessary drive and determination needed to resolve complex networking issues and meet ever changing customer demands through an evolving technology landscape.

Throughout the years of being a networking professional, I have always strived to learn more; from entry-level certifications first achieved in 2009, to my recently acquired CCIE (#60221) in Routing & Switching.

I'm now looking for a new and challenging role; one which will make best use of my existing skills and experience.

Skills

- Project Delivery
- Project Management
- LLD/HLD creation
- Technical Pre-Sales
- Cisco Meraki Wireless/Switching/MX Security appliances
- Microsoft Windows Server 2008 2016
- VMware ESXi 5.5 6.5

Layer 2

- Cisco Catalyst Switches 2000/3000/4000/6000/9000 series
- Cisco Nexus 2/5/7K

IP routing

- Cisco Routers ISR/ASR/ME
- EIGRP / BGP / OSPF / RIP / MPLS

Security Technologies

- Cisco ASA/ASAv
- Cisco FirePOWER
- Cisco ISE
- DMVPN
- IPSec / SSL Remote Access

Analysis/Automation

- Wireshark / Network Packet Capture Analysis
- Python / Unix Scripting Basic Knowledge

Experience

SICL LTD — LEEDS

SENIOR NETWORK ENGINEER – JULY 2016 – PRESENT

The Senior Network Engineer position is a role which deals with 3rd line support, project delivery / technical presales and consultancy in a managed services environment.

Duties

- Assist the sales team with technical pre-sales, identify new products and solutions, and research solutions for existing customers.
- Draft a BOM (Bill of Materials) based on customer requirements.
- Perform on-site and remote network analysis of customer infrastructure, driving innovation and opportunities for the sales team.
- Draft accurate diagrams relating to customer network infrastructure.
- Provide on-site and remote support to customers who have critical response time requirements for their business technology systems.
- Installation of equipment in data centres and customer sites.
- Work independently and as part of a team to answer service desk calls, urgently analyse technical issues, address third line escalations and mentor junior & mid-level engineers, coaching them to a resolution on complex incidents.
- Work with senior project managers on team related projects issues, and troubleshoot via phone/onsite/remote access with clients and on-site engineers.

Accomplishments

- Lead architect for a large financial institution on a data centre 6500 decommission with services moving to a Nexus 5k platform. The project included analysis, low level design, implementation of routing & switching changes in line with the scope outlined and agreed by the stakeholders.
- Technical Pre-sales / Client Consultancy / Design / Implementation of a new college building in West Cumbria, ultimately lead to additional work of an entire campus LAN refresh worth over £170,000
- Two-day on-site analysis for housing client in Coventry lead to a campus LAN refresh worth over £250,000. I was the lead engineer on both analysis, design and implementation. Work involved removing legacy equipment and following a Cisco validated routed access/collapsed core design, leveraged SD-Access capable 9300 catalyst switches at both access and core layer alongside Nexus 5k series at server access layer.
- SME for Cisco ISE, being the technical lead on multiple projects of distributed Cisco ISE deployments. Leveraging both RADIUS and TACACS+ for device administration and network access control for up to 5000 endpoint clients using the latest IBNS 2.0 framework on both IOS and IOS-XE catalyst switches.

HSBC - SHEFFIELD

3RD LINE SUPPORT NETWORK ANALYST - SEPTEMBER 2013 - JULY 2016

The role of the Network Analyst was to provide 3rd line support services for the Data Networks Europe department, supporting all business lines, as well as maintaining close working relationships with colleagues in similar roles in the Americas and Asia-Pacific regions.

Primarily responsible for maintaining and designing data networks based around Cisco systems technologies. Working as part of a team in a fast paced, changing and challenging environment.

Duties

- Acting as a technical escalation point within the 3rd line network support team.
- Prioritising and troubleshooting complex network issues. Giving quality feedback and service to alternate business areas adversely affected, at all times.
- Completing hardware implementations, upgrades and repairs
- Use of Packet capture tools to diagnose communication errors between hosts
- Take part of the on-call rota, providing 24x7x365 support when required.

Accomplishments

- Assisted on the project delivery team to migrate main data centre links from legacy Cisco 6500 series switches to Nexus 7k, involved extensive planning, testing and out of hours work to migrate.
- Primarily part of the data networks support team I was tasked with providing on-site training to voice
 engineer support colleagues on packet capture analysis, aiding them in identification of voice related
 incidents more efficiently.

HSBC - TANKERLSEY DATA CENTRE

SENIOR NETWORK OPERATOR, June 2008 - SEPTEMBER 2013

The Senior Network Operator position was a 24x7x365 1st/2nd line support role which dealt with the recovery of the IT systems, network infrastructure, and services in accordance with Business/IT SLAs in conjunction with technical support teams / 3rd party clients, and in line with the Computer and Network Operations (C&NO) incident management process.

Duties

- Keep costs at a minimum by fixing faults at first point, where applicable, without the need to escalate to out of hours 3rd line support.
- Perform scheduled tasks, investigate exceptions and faults on the network infrastructure that would alert to the team.
- Monitor a wide variety of information and network systems that include, but are not limited to telecommunications circuits, LAN/WAN systems, routers, switches, firewalls, VoIP systems.
- Escalation of problems immediately and partake on conference calls with support teams to resolve faults efficiently.
- Support the implementation of changes and action disaster recovery plans.
- Assist in the project implementation of new systems and services and assist in the upskilling of NOC team members.

Accomplishments

- Worked alongside software development teams to reduce alerts presented to the NOC, aiding false alerting and driving efficiency through the team.
- Authored technical procedures for colleagues to follow who were unfamiliar in specific technology areas, eliminating the need to contact out of hours support and reducing costs to the business.

Education

Cisco Certified Internetwork Expert #60221 (Routing & Switching)

Birmingham City University - BSc(Hons) Software Design & Networks

ITILv3 Foundation